<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: orientation | Mark Struzinski]]></title>
  <link href="http://markstruzinski.com/blog/categories/orientation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://markstruzinski.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-16T19:37:40-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://markstruzinski.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Struzinski]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orientation Changes in iOS 6]]></title>
    <link href="http://markstruzinski.com/blog/2013/03/11/orientation-changes-in-ios-6/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-11T11:05:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://markstruzinski.com/blog/2013/03/11/orientation-changes-in-ios-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a current project, I had the need to have one specific view controller present its view in landscape orientation only. Pre-iOS 6, I would have overridden the <code>shouldAutoRotateToInterfaceOrientation</code> method and returned <code>UIInterfaceOrientationLandscape</code>. In iOS 6, this method is deprecated. I began researching how orientation issues should be handled going forward, and here is the way I made my specific scenario work.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In iOS 6, the system queries the <strong>topmost</strong> visible view controller to see if it should rotate. The viewcontroller can override 2 methods to answer this query correctly:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>supportedInterfaceOrientations:</code></li>
<li><code>shouldAutoRotate</code></li>
</ul>


<p>It would seem simple enough to override these methods on each view controller that had special requirements for presentation to have them determine their orientation. The problem arose for me when I had a navigation controller thrown into the mix. Since technically the topmost view controller in a navigation stack is the navigation controller itself, iOS was ignoring the method overrides I had in place for the individual view controllers. It was sending the message directly to my UINavigationController, which did not provide the settings I needed.</p>

<p>I solved this issue by subclassing UINavigationController and overriding the previously mentioned methods, then passing the results from the navigation controller down into the top view controller via the <code>topViewController</code> property. Here are the steps to accomplish this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Create a subclass of <code>UINavigationController</code></li>
<li>Override the following methods:

<ol>
<li><code>-(UIInterfaceOrientation)preferredInterfaceOrientationForPresentation</code></li>
<li><code>-(NSUInteger)supportedInterfaceOrientations</code></li>
<li><code>-(BOOL)shouldAutorotate</code></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Return the result of each of these operations by passing in the value from the result of calling that method on the topViewControllerof the UINavigationController</li>
<li>Implement any or all of those methods specific to your needs on your UIViewController subclasses</li>
<li>Make sure you are using your <code>UINavigationController</code> subclass in place of the standard <code>UINavigationController</code>

<ol>
<li>My project uses storyboards, so I simply specified my UINavigationController subclass in the Identity Inspector</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>


<p>Here is my implementation of the navigation controller subclass in its entirety:</p>

<pre><code class="objective-c UINavigationController Subclass">
    @implementation FMNavigationController

    -(BOOL)shouldAutorotate{
        return [self.topViewController shouldAutorotate];
    }

    -(NSUInteger)supportedInterfaceOrientations{
        return [self.topViewController supportedInterfaceOrientations];
    }

    -(UIInterfaceOrientation)preferredInterfaceOrientationForPresentation{
        return [self.topViewController preferredInterfaceOrientationForPresentation];
    }

    @end
</code></pre>

<p>Then, in my specific view controller that needs to be launched in landscape, I overrode this method and returned the appropriate value:</p>

<pre><code class="objective-c View Controller Method Overrides">
    #pragma mark - Rotation
    -(NSUInteger)supportedInterfaceOrientations{
        return UIInterfaceOrientationMaskLandscape;
    }
</code></pre>

<p>That’s really all there was to it. The research to get this right took much longer than the implementation.</p>

<p>Please contact me with any questions, and good luck.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
